Guide to the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Durham, NC records, 1894-1992 RL.11616
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Files, 1894-1992
  - Board of Directors, 1894-1990; 3
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1933 (Box 24)
      Harriet Tubman Branch correspondence.
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1933-1934 (Box 24)
      Harriet Tubman Branch correspondence and financial materials.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1933-1935 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1934 (Box 24)
      Harriet Tubman Branch correspondence, finance, and annual meeting.
    - Board Meeting and Committee Materials, 1935-1947 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1936-1937 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1938-1939 (Box 24)
    - Board Materials, 1939-1949 (Box 24)
      Financial committee and national correspondence.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1940-1942 (Box 24)
    - Community Chest Campaign, 1942-1950 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1943-1945 (Box 24)
    - Board Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 24)
    - Health Education Committee, 1943-1949 (Box 24)
    - Workers Education Community Fund, 1944-1945 (Box 24)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1946-1949 (Box 24)
    - Finance Reports, 1947 (Box 25)
    - Board Materials, 1947-1949 (Box 25)
    - Youth programming, 1946-1954 (Box 25)
    - Material Relating to Building, 1947-1961 (Box 25)
    - Budgets and Financial Reports, 1948 (Box 25)
    - Membership Committee, 1948-1955 (Box 25)
    - Budgets and Financial Reports, 1949 (Box 25)
    - Annual Meetings, 1949-1956 (Box 25)
    - Insurance Bonds, 1949-1959 (Box 25)
    - History of the Durham YWCA, [1948] (Box 25)
    - National Quota, 1949-1965 (Box 25)
    - Board Materials, 1950s (Box 25)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1950 (Box 25)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1950-1953 (Box 25)
    - National Support, 1950-1969 (Box 25)
    - Annual Meetings, 1950-1958 (Box 25)
    - Board Materials, 1951-1957 (Box 25)
      Includes minutes, financial committee meetings, national correspondence, and constitution/by-laws.
    - Committee Reports, 1951-1958 (Box 25)
    - Monthly Reports from Departments, 1952-1955 (Box 25)
    - Pest Control, 1952-1958 (Box 25)
    - Health Education Department, 1952-1963 (Box 25)
    - Annual Meeting and Branch Committee, 1952-1954 (Box 25)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 25)
    - Residence Polices and Correspondence, 1953-1956 (Box 25)
    - Residence Inventory, 1953-1957 (Box 26)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1953-1959 (Box 26)
    - Annual Meetings, 1953-1959 (Box 26)
    - United Fund of Durham, 1953-1961 (Box 26)
    - Board Minutes and Committee Materials, 1953-1969 (Box 26)
    - Roll Call of Professional Staff, 1953-1971 (Box 26)
    - Departmental Annual Survey, 1954 (Box 26)
    - Petty Cash, 1954-1955 (Box 26)
    - Constitution and Bylaws and Revisions, 1954-1979 (Box 26)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1954-1955 (Box 26)
    - Tile for Basement Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 26)
    - Material on Property, 1954-1955 (Box 26)
    - Publicity, 1954-1956 (Box 26)
    - Sanitary Regualtions and Inspection, 1954-1971 (Box 26)
    - Special Committee on Exchange of Property, 1955 (Box 26)
      Official correspondence about widening Chapel Hill Street.
    - Social Planning Council, 1955 (Box 26)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 26)
    - United Fund Budget Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 26)
    - Sales and Use Tax Report, 1955-1965 (Box 26)
    - Material for Budget Hearing, 1955-1959 (Box 26)
    - Employee Retirement Funds, 1955-1968 (Box 26)
    - Board Meeting Minutes: Board Secretary copy, 1956-1961 (Box 26)
    - Annual Meeting, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Staff Schedules, 1957 (Box 26)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 26)
    - Board Materials, 1957-1959 (Box 26)
      Personnel committee, staff hiring, job restructuring.
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1957-1959 (Box 26)
    - Budget Materials, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Rich Plan, 1958-1960 (Box 26)
    - Building Fund, 1958-1961 (Box 27)
    - Personnel, 1958-1971 (Box 27)
    - Budget Information, 1959-1961 (Box 27)
    - Board Materials, 1960-1963 (Box 27)
      Personnel committee and finances.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1961-1963 (Box 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 27)
    - Branch Committee Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 27)
    - Board Materials, 1963-1964 (Box 27)
      Personnel, finances, and 1964 Annual Meeting.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1963-1968 (Box 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1963-1969 (Box 27)
    - Board and Committee meeting minutes, 1963-1969 (Box 27)
    - Board Materials, 1965-1970 (Box 27)
      Personnel committee, annual reports, annual meeting, and board nominating materials.
    - Annual Meeting, 1965 (Box 27)
    - YWCA By Laws, 1966 (Box 27)
    - McDougal Terrace Day Care Center Bond, 1966 (Box 27)
    - National Support, 1968 (Box 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 27)
    - Evaluation, 1969 (Box 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 27)
    - Board Materials, 1970-1972 (Box 27)
      Finances and a history of the Durham YWCA.
    - Constitution Revision, 1973-1975 (Box 27)
    - Nominating Committee Materials, 1974-1980 (Box 27)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 27)
    - Affirmative Action Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 27)
    - Advisory Board, 1975-1976 (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors Materials, 1975-1980 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1987 (Box 28)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 28)
    - Finance Committee, 1976-1980 (Box 28)
    - Board of Directors Working File, 1978-1979 (Box 28)
      Includes meetings and reports from the Board of Directors and Board Committees.
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 28)
    - Board Book, 1979-1980 (Box 28)
    - Board Minutes, 1979 (Box 28)
    - Board Committees, 1980 (Box 28)
    - Board Minutes, 1980 (Box 28)
    - Board Minutes and Financials, 1981; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - Board Minutes, 1981 (Box 28)
    - Budget Material, 1981 (Box 28)
    - Budget Materials, 1982 (Box 29)
    - By-laws and Constitution, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Board of Directors meetings and committee reports, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Committee Meetings, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Board of Directors Materials, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Board Calendar, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Board Lists, 1982 (Box 29)
    - Board Meetings and Program Reports, 1982 July-December (Box 29)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1982 May-October (Box 29)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1983 January-December (Box 29)
    - Administrative Division Meetings, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Board Meetings and Program Reports, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Budget, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Budget Request, 1983 (Box 29)
    - Board Book, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Board Minutes, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Annual Report and Meeting, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Board Book, 1985 (Box 30)
    - YW Wake Strategic Planning Task Force Committee, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Board Administration, 1986 (Box 30)
      Includes copy of YWCA letter in support of the Durham Pride March
    - Annual Report, 1986 (Box 30)
    - Board Minutes and Reports, 1986 (Box 30)
    - Board Book, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1987 August-October (Box 30)
    - Board Meetings, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Annual Report, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Executive Director Report, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Board Subcommittees and Chairs, 1988 (Box 30)
    - Board Meetings, 1988 (Box 30)
    - Pauline Frazier, 1988 (Box 30)
      Letters from the board, reciepts, and a few legal files about Pauline Frazier's removal from her position.
    - National Board Career Development Project and Local Board Organization/Meetings, 1989-1990 (Box 30)
  - Women's Center, 5
    - Durham Interagency Council on Community Education and Recreation, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - North Carolina Cluster, 1979-1982 (Box 41)
    - Employment, 1975-1982 (Box 41)
      Includes correspondence and notes.
    - Programming, 1975-1979 (Box 41)
    - Women's Resource Center Agenda, 1980-1983 (Box 41)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Flyers, PSA's, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Women's Fair, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Structure, Goals, Organization, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Fundraising, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Membership Lists, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Budget & Finance, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous & Program (Workshop) Info, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Development, 1985 (Box 41)
    - General Child Care, 1980-1985 (Box 41)
    - Boards & Comm, n.d. (Box 41)
    - Child Care Task Force, 1984-1985 (Box 41)
    - Retreat, 1984-1985 (Box 41)
    - DICCER, 1984-1986 (Box 41)
    - Copying, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Health Co-op, 1974-1986 (Box 41)
    - Women's Center Task Force, 1982 (Box 41)
- Program Files, 1924-1989
  - YWCA Programs, 1924-1989; 1
    - YWCA Program and Office Forms, 1980-1989; 25 folders (Box 34)
      Training and Roleplay Evaluations, typing request forms, United Way forms, victims assistance, victim contact, volunteer screening, volunteer agreement, volunteer evaluation and self-evaluation, YWCA program development, program creation, program planning, and time sheets.
    - Partner Agencies (Durham) Files, 1980-1989; 57 folders (Box 34)
      Acorn, ACRA, ACR-Durham, AVSA, Baby Love, Center for Early Adolescence, Coalition for the Early Prevention of Adolescent Pregnancies, Child Advocacy Commission, Coordinating Senior Citizens, DCPCA, Duke Counseling and Health, Federal Parent Locator, 14th Judicial District, Guardian Ad Litem, Harpo, Healthy Children and Teens, Helpline, Incest Survivors Anon, Lesbian Health, National AIDS Hotline, NC Careline, NC Center for Missing Persons, NCDPT Crime Control/Safety, Orange County Commission for Women, Orange County Planned Parenthood, Our Place, Teen Link, Trinity House, UNC Family Center
    - Media Files, 1980-1989; 18 folders (Box 34)
      Carolina Times, Charlie Goodnight, Durham Advertiser, Durham Morning Herald, Media Mailing Lists, PBS Television, Public Service Announcements, RCC Newsletter, Triangle Observer
    - Politician Files, 1980-1989; 12 folders (Box 34)
      Representatives, Governor Martin, Sen. Biden, Sen. Jesse Helms, Sen. Hunt, Rep. Michaux, Rep. Miller, Rep. Rodino, Sen. Royall, Sen. Terry Stanford, Rep. S. Thompson, Rep. Tim Valentine.
    - Durham School Files, 1980-1989; 3 folders (Box 34)
      Durham County Schools, NC Science and Math, Neal and Githens.
    - Personnel Records, 1980-1989; 82 folders (Box 34, Box 35)
      Records of personnel who taught classes, programs, and workshops at the YWCA.
    - Organizational Contacts, n.d. (Box 35)
      Contacts for organizations to put on programs at the YWCA.
    - Program Brochures and Pamphlets, 1942-1961 (Box 35)
    - Fall Setting Up Conference, 1944 (Box 35)
    - Promotional Materials, 1944 (Box 35)
    - USO Council and Leadership Institute, 1944-1947 (Box 35)
    - Industrial Club, 1946 (Box 35)
    - Industrial Club Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 35)
    - Camps for Girls, 1947-1950 (Box 35)
    - Neighborhood Conference, 1947 (Box 35)
    - Greensboro Y-Teens, 1947 (Box 35)
    - Camp Committee, 1948 (Box 35)
    - Program Planning, 1948-1949 (Box 35)
    - Social Workers Roundtable and UNWEO Mothers Project, 1948-1955 (Box 35)
    - Camp, 1950 (Box 36)
    - Conference on Marriage and Family, 1950 (Box 35)
    - Crafts, 1950-1952 (Box 36)
    - Programs and Program Planning, 1950-1951 (Box 35)
    - Residents Meeting Minutes, 1957-1969 (Box 36)
    - YWCA Residents and Program Photos, 1950-1979; 13 folders (Box 35, Box 36)
      Photos of Harriet Tubman Branch residents, summer camp, adult activities, special guests/special occasions, and association wide.
    - YWCA Station Wagon, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Open House Publicity Material, 1957 (Box 36)
    - Classes and Programs, 1957 (Box 36)
    - Health Education Coordinator, 1958-1962 (Box 36)
    - Program Brochures and Pamphlets, 1959-1964 (Box 36)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1960s (Box 36)
    - Sexism in Schools, 1960-1979 (Box 36)
    - Desk Schedules, 1963-1967 (Box 36)
    - Fall and Winter Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 36)
    - Special Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 36)
    - Matrons Club Minutes, 1971-1974 (Box 36)
    - Camp Director's Handbook, 1976 (Box 36)
    - Publicity, 1976-1978 (Box 36)
    - Newsletters, program brochures, and materials from other NC YWCAs, 1976-1978 (Box 36)
    - Women's Health Co-op Training, 1976-1978 (Box 36)
    - PR, 1980-1989 (Box 36)
    - Administrative Aspects of a YWCA Program, 1980-1989 (Box 36)
    - Southern Harvest: A Folkart Event Evaluation, 1981-1982 (Box 36)
    - Coalition for Battered Women Steering Committee, 1982 (Box 36)
    - Program Planning, 1983 (Box 36)
    - YWCA Program Ideas and Interested Students, 1983 (Box 36)
    - Day Camp Food Service, 1983 (Box 36)
    - Fall Newsletter, 1983 (Box 36)
    - Newsletters, 1983-1984 (Box 36)
    - YWCA Public Relations, 1984 (Box 37)
    - Durham Day Care Council, 1984-1987 (Box 37)
    - Materials from other YWCAs, 1984-1985 (Box 37)
    - Women of Achievement Awards, 1985; 11 folders (Box 37)
      Includes nominees from science, health, public service, education and business, as well as winners and committee members.
    - The Downtown Club and Broomstick Newsletter, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - Women's Rights and Women of Achievement materials, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Women of Achievement Award Nominations, 1986; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Arts Mailing List, n.d. (Box 37)
    - Arts in the Y, 1985 (Box 37)
    - Durham Arts Council, 1987 (Box 37)
    - Durham Arts Council/CTR Fest, 1987 (Box 37)
    - YWCA Clippings, 1985 (Box 37)
    - YWCA Publicity, 1985-1987 (Box 37)
    - YWCA Information (history, people, etc.), 1986 (Box 37)
    - PR, 1986 (Box 37)
    - YWCA Flyers, 1986-1987 (Box 37)
    - Other Y Flyers and Brochures, 1986-1987 (Box 37)
    - Social Justice, 1986-1987 (Box 37)
    - Program Budget Expenditures, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Projected Program Budget, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Adult Programs, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Button, Button Poetic Drama Performance, 1987 (Box 38)
    - South Carolina Islands Trip, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Women-International Working, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Women Who Love Too Much, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Nine to Five Conference, n.d. (Box 38)
    - NC Coalition for Choice Newsletter, 1987 (Box 38)
    - NC Coalition for Choice Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Matrons Club, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Mixology Class, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Publications--In Harmony, 1987 (Box 38)
      Partner organization of the YWCA.
    - American Cancer Society Programming, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Local Newsletters, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Other Organization Newsletter, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Southern Growth Policy Board, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Programs, 1987-1988 (Box 38)
    - Women's History Month, 1987 (Box 38)
    - YWCA World Mutual Service Program, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Durham Walk for Health, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Encore Physical Fitness Program, 1987 (Box 38)
    - Program Budget, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Durham Interagency Council, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Loose scrapbook materials, 1950-1951 (Box 38)
    - Aerobics, n.d. (Box 39)
    - After Work Exercise Christine Funcik, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
    - Art Work, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Battered Woman Project Grant, pt. 1, 1977-1980 (Box 39)
    - Battered Woman Project Grant, pt. 2, 1977-1980 (Box 39)
    - Computer Classes, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Cooking, 1987 (Box 39)
    - DICCER, 1989 (Box 39)
    - Durham County Council for Women, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
    - Flyers, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Hannah Harrison School Wash. D.C. Vacational Training, 1956-1976 (Box 39)
    - Industrial Outreach Noontime Program (Box 39)
    - Josephine Clement, Speaker, 1984 (Box 39)
    - Kwanza, 1984-1988 (Box 39)
    - Lynn Charleton Prenatal Fitness, n.d. (Box 39)
    - Matron Club, 1983-1984 (Box 39)
    - Matron's Club Written Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 39)
    - Matron's Club Written Minutes, 1962-1967 (Box 39)
    - MCC Summer Camp, 1989 (Box 39)
    - The Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
    - Newsletters, 1986-1987 (Box 39)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1924-1932 (Box 39)
    - Peace Site, 1987 (Box 39)
    - Post Abortion Support, 1985 (Box 39)
    - Program Info General, 1985-1987 (Box 39)
    - Programs/Publicity, 1983-1988 (Box 39)
    - Project Committee Bicycle Safety Triangles, 1975-1977 (Box 39)
    - P.W.P., 1972-1979 (Box 39)
    - Teen Mentor Program, 1988 (Box 39)
    - Teen/Peer Counselors Programs, 1989 (Box 39)
    - Teen Pregnancy Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 39)
    - Women of Achievement, 1983-1989 (Box 39)
    - Workshops on Racism, 1982-1984 (Box 39)
    - YWCA Community Meeting-Information, 1989 (Box 39)
    - YWCA-Ideas, 1975-1979 (Box 39)
    - YWCA Publicity Brochure, n.d. (Box 39)
    - YWCA-YWCA Relationships, 1953-1978 (Box 39)
    - 1985 YWCA Misc., 1985-1986 (Box 39)
    - 1986 YWCA Misc., 1986-1987 (Box 39)
      Correspondence and pamphlets.
    - YWCA Misc., 1947-1975 (Box 39)
    - Past Programs, n.d. (Box 91)
    - Visitor's Registry, 1927-1949 (Box 91)
    - PSA's, 1984-1985 (Box 91)
    - Counseling + Mental Health for Adults, n.d. (Box 91)
    - Consumerism, n.d. (Box 91)
    - Membership, 1983-1984 (Box 91)
    - Button, Button Who Has the Button?, 1983 (Box 91)
    - Public Affairs, 1980-1983 (Box 91)
    - The Voting Rights Act Unfulfilled Goals and More Hurdles to Clear Women and Girls in Competitive Athletics, 1980-1981 (Box 91)
    - Training and Visiting Speakers, 1981-1988 (Box 91)
    - Flyers and Event Programs, 1986-1988 (Box 91)
    - National and International YWCA Pamphlets, 1967-1985 (Box 92)
    - Travel the Roads of Progress with the HT Branch YWCA, 1979 (Box 92)
    - Affirmative Action to Open the Doors of Job Opportunity, 1984 (Box 92)
    - YWCA Interchange, 1982-1984 (Box 92)
    - Sign-up Sheet MCC, n.d. (Box 92)
    - Swimming + H2O Safety, n.d. (Box 92)
    - Concerned Seniors and Friends (Box 92)
    - Women of Achievement Committees, 1983-1986 (Box 92)
    - YWCA Brochures, 1955-1974; 3 folders (Box 93)
    - YWCA Brochures and Membership Registration, 1970-1975 (Box 93)
  - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989; 2
    - Scrapbooks, 1952-1963; 15 boxes (Box 13)
      Scrapbooks created by various YWCA program groups, including Y Teens, residents, and other clubs. Scrapbooks include photographs, newspaper clippings, brochures, newsletters, and flyers for programs or events at both of the YWCA branches.
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1950 (Box 14)
    - Scrapbook, 1969 (Box 15)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 4)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 5)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 6)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 7)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 8)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 9)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 10)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 11)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 13)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Oversize-box 14)
    - Scrapbooks, 1936-1989 (Box 17)
  - Membership, 1944-1978; 3
    - Salisbury-Thompson, 1944-1965 (Box 44)
      Membership cards of Durham YWCA members at both the Central and Harriet Tubman branches. Includes programs attended by members.
    - Thompson-Turner, Eades-Gordon, 1945-1957 (Box 45)
    - Gore-Pettiford, 1944-1960 (Box 46)
    - Porter-Rigsbee, Amey-Mitchell, 1945-1972 (Box 47)
    - Mitchiner-Young, Cox-Dick, Adams-Wilson, 1944-1977 (Box 48)
    - Wilson-Shaw, 1944-1964 (Box 49)
      Includes Y-Teen Membership cards.
    - Abdalla-Kaufman, 1973-1976 (Box 50)
    - Lachowitch-Zurer, 1975-1978 (Box 51)
    - Harrison-Zimmerman, 1966-1972 (Box 52)
    - Abdullah-Zurer, Ray-Cannady (deceased), Beasley-Zampighi, 1976-1979 (Box 53)
    - Agner-Wynne, Chesnut-Marsh, Aiken-Young, Adkins-Zimmerman, Kearney-Lyons, 1958-1976 (Box 54)
    - Lyons-Myhand, 1947-1964 (Box 55)
    - Veit-White, 1954-1967 (Box 56)
    - Wilson-Seundy, 1947-1953 (Box 57)
- Community Outreach, 1965-1988
  The Community Outreach series consists of records from the Durham Women's Health Cooperative and the Rape Crisis Center of Durham as well as those related to general outreach programming. They consist of informational pamphlets, training materials, flyers, periodicals, excerpts from periodicals, legislative summaries, administrative records, and newsletters.
  - Durham Women's Health Co-op Files, 1965-1980; 1
    The Durham Women's Health Cooperative became attached to the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) in the 1970's. The records encompass correspondence with other women's health organizations, informational pamphlets, healthcare provider surveys, training materials, periodical excerpts and full-length periodicals on women's health issues, legislative summaries, and administrative records. Although the Durham Women's Health Cooperative primarily focused on women's health concerns, the records from the organization also include informational pamphlets and trainings around men's health topics, such as sterilization. A notable feature of the collection are the Doctor and Consumer Surveys; they are anonymous reviews of different health practioners in the area that give a perspective of women's experience of health care.
    - 2BBCC General Information, 1975; 1 folders (Box 59)
      The records are arranged alphabetically.
    - Abortion A.S.A. Newsletter, Reprints, etc., 1971-1974; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Coalition for Choice, 1978-1979; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Counseling, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion groups- MORAL, N.A.C., 1977; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Information-1, 1976-1980; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Information-2, 1971-1979; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion-NARAL, Coalition for Choice, 1978; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Procedures Outline, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion R.C.A.R.- "Options" Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion Sources (Clinics), 1977; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Abortion-Washington Clinics, 1974; 1 folders (Box 59)
      Information about abortion care at different facilities.
    - Adolescent Pregnancy, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Adoption, 1970-1977; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Anatomy- Female- Definitions, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Anatomy- Female- Diagram, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Anatomy- Male- Diagram, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Articles OB-GYN, 1976-1978; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Attendance Records (filled out), 1978-1979; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Battered Women: Conference Packets 4/1977 Newsletter, 1977-1978; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Bibliography- Women & Health, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Bibliography- Women & Health Care and MISC. Book Information, 1975-1980; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Birth Control Counseling, 1979; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Birth Control Flyer, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 59)
    - Birth Control in general, 1970-1979; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Birth Control IUD, 1975; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Birth Control Male, 1973-1979; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Birth Control Pill, 1974-1977; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Breast Cancer, 1978-1979; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Bronx Community Abortion Center (N.Y.), 1972; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Caregiving: A Student Guide to Personal and Community Health, 1978; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Cervical Caps, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Child, Adolescent & Teen- General (non-pregnancy), 1979; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Childbirth, breast feeding, 1973-1978; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Childbirth Information, 1976-1980; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Coalition for Teen Awareness, 1978; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Community Events Street Arts Celebration Apple Chill, etc. Etc., 1978; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Contraception Training Handouts, 1975-1980; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1979; 1 folders (Box 60)
    - Cosmetics, 1976; 1 folders (Box 60)